

samyaksah.github.io

ssah@sfu.ca 🖂

samyaksah

about

I am a user experience designer with an aim to create genuine human centric designs that empowers users to live a better life. I like critical, empathetic and ethical aspects of designing.

academic projects

Service Design

Sept 2019 - Dec 2019 Vancouver, Canada (Academic)

Rain City Games

A 13-week project in collaboration with a specialty board game shop. Responsible for extensive ethnographic study of 160+ customers in-store to find their needs, motives and pain points. Took part in design sprints to ideate on the final solution and responsible for creating as well as user-testing physical prototypes in-store with 70+ customers.

education

Simon Fraser University

Expected Graduation: Fall 2021

Senior student in the School of Interactive Arts and Technology (SIAT) focusing on interaction design, product design, and user experience.

Design Evaluation

Nov 2019 - Dec 2019 Vancouver, Canada (Academic)

Microsoft Teams

A 2-week project consisting of evaluating Microsoft Teams. Responsible for conducting usability evaluations with participants followed by facilitating a 7 day field deployment and extensive post-study interview sessions. Also created affinity diagrams based on the insights to provide critical suggestions to improve the usability of the app.

skills

Interaction
Interface
User Research
Visual
Journey Mapping

Motion Wireframing Prototyping Personas

UX/UI Case Study

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019 Vancouver, Canada (Academic)

Lunular

An 8-week product design project where my team and I designed an app for nail enthusiasts. Lunular is an AR Based try-on tool for users who have a hard time deciding on the perfect nail-color that would suit them. The app also serves as a place to find trustworthy and reputable salons that are worth the price.

3D Animation

Oct 2018 - Dec 2018 Vancouver, Canada (Academic)

Ignition

Ignition is a short 3D animation developed in Autodesk Maya and edited on Adobe programs over a course of 3 months. It is a fake trailer of an immersive VRRPG where players take part in a dangerous car race on a track filled with traps.



samyaksah.github.io

ssah@sfu.ca

samyaksah

tools

Figma
Adobe XD
Photoshop

InDesign

Illustrator HTML+CSS Lightroom

work experience

Web and Visual Designer

May 2018 - present Vancouver, Canada (Freelance)

Quality Education Asia

Created promotional posters (print + digital), signage, merchandise and edited educational videos for a company that facilitates educating teachers. Maintained pre-built php based website and adding pages as required.

3D+video

After Effects Premiere Pro Blender Sony Vegas Autodesk Maya

Graphic Design Teaching Assitant

Jan 2018 - Jan 2019 Vancouver, Canada (Paid Job)

Fraser International College

Facilitated 4 lab section/week for approximately 80 students. Taught introductory level Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign and Muse to students, providing one-on-one feedback on assignments.

interests

Comics Games Storytelling Animation Movies

Design Executive

Jan 2017 - May 2018 Vancouver, Canada (Volunteer)

Indian Student Federation

Created visually stimulating information posters(print + digital) and videos for a club that organises Indian festivals for university students. Designed merchandise (hoodies, tags etc.) for the executives of the club.

Digital Designer

Jan 2017 - May 2017 Vancouver, Canada (Freelance)

Campskil Cooperation

Created digital + print posters for a startup that facilitates skill based educational events for university students all over India.